what's one over one plus one over two
plus one over three so on forever you
keep adding positive values so maybe
it's infinity but the numbers are
getting smaller and smaller so maybe
this sum is finite
here's the one represented as an area
here's the one half as an area the
one-third and so on forever
and here's the function one over x
graphed from one to infinity
notice how the rectangles line up nicely
and more importantly notice that the
area of the rectangles is larger than
the area under the curve of the function
you can use technology or calculus to
find the area under this curve and
realize it's infinite
yet the area of the rectangles is bigger
than that
since the area of the rectangles
represent our sum
we have our answer
so now what if i ask you this question